María P. Maldonado

Translator, Content Writer, Virtual Assistant

Colombia, remote | +57 3144260215

mariap.maldonado@gmail.com | https://sites.google.com/view/mariapomv/about-me https://www.linkedin.com/in/mariapomv/

Experienced Translator and Content Writer with a proven track record of creating engaging content for tourism blogs using SEO strategies and keywords. Skilled Virtual Assistant with a year of experience in managing social media calendars and generating leads.

EXPERIENCE

Virtual Assistant Sep 2022 - Mar 2023

Staffaro

- Created 15+ online courses, 5-10 modules each in the Systeme.io platform, resulting in 100+ enrollments.
- Managed 2 Facebook groups about SaaS, resulting in a 20% increase in engagement.
- Uploaded 10+ videos on YouTube, resulting in 100+ views each.
- Created 10+ images and flyers for social media using Canva tool, resulting in a 10% increase in website traffic.
- Scheduled 2 social media calendars for a cleaning services brand using Loomly, resulting in a 15% increase in engagement.
- Wrote 12+ topics for newsletters using ChatGPT AI, resulting in a 25% increase in open rates.
- Searched 100+ leads on LinkedIn Sales Navigator and put information into Google Spreadsheets, resulting in a 15% increase in sales leads.

Health Services Representative

Oct 2021 - Apr 2022

Teleperformance

- Assisted senior US citizens with their copayments, authorizations, medical procedures, and other health-related matters, resulting in a 95% customer satisfaction rate.
- Managed complex systems on Salesforce, resulting in a 50% increase in productivity.

Master Support

Sep 2020 - Sep 2022

L2C Productions S.A.S

Assisted and guided webcam models to engage with US and Worldwide users for the purpose of having private shows on adult websites such as SC, CS, F4F, and LJ with no physical contact, resulting in a 60% increase in content sales.

Virtual Assistant Jun 2020 - Sep 2020

Valatam

Learned how to performed the following tasks, increasing in 50% in effectivity and efficiency:

- Online research
- Lead generation
- Writing about a variety of topics
- Scheduling SM calendars

Freelancer Content Writer and Translator

Jun 2017 - May 2020

Upwork/HoyEnTec

- Managed content creation, translation, and proofreading for a technology blog with over 50 articles rewritten, translated, and uploaded from Google News.
- Implemented basic SEO and used WordPress editor to optimize articles for search engines.
- Authored over 40 articles for a tourism blog, covering a range of topics and engaging readers with informative, entertaining content.

• Built and maintained relationships with clients, consistently meeting deadlines and delivering high-quality work.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Modern Languages - Foreign Languages Sep 2012 - Oct 2018 *University of Los Andes*

5-year university degree with subjects related to the culture, phonetics, literature, and linguistics of both studied languages, English and French. Minor in Translation of general, scientific-technical, legal, and literary texts.

SKILLS

Expert in: Translating

Intermediate in: Content Writer, Virtual Assistance, Customer Care Services, Google Docs,

Google Spreadsheets, Canva, Slack

Basic in: Trello, Loomly, SEO

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native (C2)

English: Fluent/Advanced (C1)

French: Basic (A2)